First, let's think about the dream. Let's think
about
what our kind of popular culture has
depicted artificial intelligence as
in the movies over time.
So it's possible you've seen some of
these movies.
Does anybody recognize this?
Who's the tall yellow one?
That's C-3PO. What does C-3PO do?
C-3PO is the protocol droid, human-cyborg relations, right? He's
basically Google translate,
with anxiety, right?
Okay, how about R2-D2, what does he do?
Yeah, I, I have no idea what he does
actually...
But the point is both of them, they're
helpful,
they're well-meaning, they're good, right, and
it's a very positive view on what technology can bring.
This was the seventies.
Things kind of got darker in our
popular culture view of technology,
and this goes through a wide range of
genres, not just movies and so we
started worrying. Wait a minute,
maybe the robots won't translate for us
and beep around,
maybe there's gonna be killer hardware
from the future coming back to kill us.
It's a very different view, right, and
you know they kinda looked the same--uh,
maybe not but it's a very different view of
the future. It's very scary, right. The
scary hardware coming back, really with malice.
We're now a little bit afraid of the
technology.
That was the eighties. What about the
nineties? In the nineties we learned that
actually, software is scary.
And then what's happened since then? Well since then you know we've thought of a lot of ideas but
really the basic fear
of what technology might do if it
goes wrong
hasn't gone away.
Now we worry about things like, what if
kind of the evil technology turns on us
and maybe actually we can't even tell
us apart from them.
Or, maybe the technology won't just look
like us,
maybe instead the technology will be
evil and
... really snarky.
And so we're not really sure what we're afraid of,
but kind of we know we're afraid. Okay, there's
exceptions like WALL-E that have a
somewhat uplifting view of what technology
might bring, at least after we destroy ourselves.
But, by and large there's this thread of
worrying about what AI might do.
Okay, that's the science fiction story,
that's the worry, right--
I'm not very worried about these things,
at present.